見られてる　どこからか…
We'll all use the closest exit,
and bust in from beside the central stairway.
とりあえず　キルアを待とう
And the stronger the Nen,
the bigger my stomach gets.
よぉ　待たせたな。
I should ask Leol-sama for a larger reward!
感じるだろ　べっとりと へばりつくような視線。
Right, Shidore?
人間特有の湿り具合だ。 やっぱり　みんな　気づいてる
Having a peon that understands
speech is useful, but...
まぁ　こんな距離から 気づかれてるようじゃ 大した奴らじゃ　ねえ
You really need to talk more.
見られてるな。 ん？
You have permission to shoot her on sight!
キルア！ お待た。
As a foreigner, she can't blend
in with the other citizens!
街らしき影は　全然見えないな。
Damn! Damn that woman!
そうなんだけど みんな　似た方角に向かったよ。
What does she want?
ふん…　あっちか　こっちだろ？
Hey!
でも問題は　何で　こっちを 見張ってるかってことだな。
How many times have I told you
not to use your cell phone here?
確かに…。 さて　行くか！
The radio waves irritate my ears,
and it gives me a headache!
見てる奴が　どんな奴だろうと まずは情報収集だ。
Plus, I can hear what you're saying. Next time I catch you, I'll snap your
phone and your arm in half.
で　どうだった？ ん？ お前のセーブデータさ。
W-Well... There are urgent matters
that must be dealt with.
ブック！
I need to use my phone.
カード　何枚ぐらい入ってた？ 一枚も入ってなかった。 えっ　マジ？
It's so urgent that you find
the woman who ran away?
でも　ジンからの メッセージはあったよ。
I can find her for you.
何て？ 「ゲームを楽しめ」って。 「ゲームを楽しめ」か…。
R-Really? My nose happens to be very sharp...
でも　ここがゲームの中だって実感 全然ないけどな。
If you have something she wore, I can track her.
ブック。 キルアは　このゲームのルール 聞いて　どう思う？
The Royal Guard appreciates the work you do, and I respect you, as well!
うん… まだ　全く未知数って感じだな。
So, a little give-and-take will benefit us both here. O-Okay!
何だ？　今の… 念能力かな？
I will become the King behind the scenes. To accomplish that, I must be friendly
with Bizeff, not with the King.
君達　ゲームは初めてだろ。 さて　どうかな。
Welfin-sama, an urgent alert has been issued. Bah.
本を持ってるってことは あんたもプレーヤーだね。
When peons send transmissions,
it gives me a headache.
フン　とぼけても無駄さ
This smells like... Taragette's blood.
ゲーム初心者なのは　バレバレ
There are bloodstains and dirty shoes.
ここは 「スティール」のカードで…
An intruder! If he took his shoes off here
to avoid leaving footprints, he must be somewhere deeper within.
一体　何してやがるんだ？
He didn't hide his shoes because he had a pressing mission and
couldn't afford to lose time...
ふん　キルアくんと　ゴンくんか。
That day last week, when it rained?
何で名前が分かったの？ さて　何でかな。
That was the day Taragette went missing.
ヘヘヘ…　スペルカードも 知らないようじゃ
I'm pretty sure that the intruder killed him.
話にならないぜ
But that means he disposed of Taragette's body
決定的だな こいつら　来たばかりの 完全初心者　しかもガキ
If he wrapped the body in something to move it, he must have come prepared. Was kidnapping a soldier his mission?
こいつらに　このスペルを 使うのは　もったいない
Why would they do that?! Damn, I don't get this!
「トレース」で十分！ 「トレース」オン！ キルアを攻撃！
Should I ask Shaiapouf for advice? No, I'll catch the intruder,
and get the answers from him.
ゲームのスペルからは どうやったって逃げらんねえよ！
He did head inside the palace!
あっ！ キルア！　大丈夫!?
This guy comes before Bizeff's woman...
ヘヘヘ…　攻撃成功！
Follow me!
こいつ…　ヤバい！
What is your name?
「リターン」オン！
It's K-K-Komugi.
マサドラへ！
Can you please tell me what your name is?
シズク　コルトピ ちょっと　いいかな。
I can't wait to play him again!
どうせ　本拠地に戻っても 予定はないだろ？ そんなに　ゲームを クリアしたいの？
Who am I?
実は　ゲームのクリアが 目的じゃないんだ。
A nameless king... in a borrowed castle.
「旅団」の活動に 関係ありってこと？ まぁね。
My subjects are mindless puppets.
分かった。 いいよ。 キルア　体のほう大丈夫？
If this is the fate that the
heavens have granted me...
ん？　別に変わりはないぜ。 でも心配だな。 何かされたのは 間違いないんだし。
I have no doubt that I shall
be slowly bored to death!
魔法？　どんな？
Don't follow me.
さぁな　まぁ　そのうち分かるだろ。 うん…。
Yes, but—
あっ！　街だ！
Do not make me repeat myself.
懸賞って　あれのことか？
Now we've all been beaten by the King.
うわ！　これ全部　懸賞？ …みてぇだな。 あっ　キルア！　あれ！
The King says your En is irritating him.
「アントキバ月例大会行事表」…。
I figured he would be saying that soon.
今月は　ジャンケン大会だってさ。
But I can't remove our security...
優勝賞品は「真実の剣」。
Then you go and tell him that!
重要なアイテムなのかな？ 恐らくな。
I don't want another beating.
あっち見てみ。 ん？
How does this sound?
あっちにも。
We can block all aura in a radius
surrounding Your Majesty.
参加してみる？ 当然。 じゃあ　せっかくだから いろんな懸賞に挑戦しようよ！
This way, my presence will not bother you.
情報収集も しなきゃいけないしな。
Are you telling me to stay in one place?
いらっしゃい！ ３０分以内に完食すれば お代はタダ！
the aura-free zone around me
while I move wouldn't be possible.
さらに　賞品の「ガルガイダー」を プレゼント！
I refuse to have my movement
constantly monitored.
それでは　スタート！
No, that would not be our proposal.
ねぇ　おっちゃん 魔法って　どうやったら使えんの？
So if I do not wish to deal with your presence,
I will only be able to move
何だ？　そりゃ。
within that confined area.
じゃあ　この街で 一番の物知りって誰？ モノシリ？　何だ？　そりゃ。
I must order you to move that zone
should I wish to go elsewhere?
この人　何も知らないね。
There is nothing more I can say.
やっぱり 単なるゲームキャラなんだよ。
Keep your En focused outside the palace.
アイヤ！　やられたね！ はい！　賞品の「ガルガイダー」ね。
I shall put up with that until tomorrow's selection. Are you dissatisfied?
「１２１７　Ｆ－１８５」。
Should that not suffice to guard
against outside attacks?
これ　何のことだろう？ 君達　カード　初めてなのか？
Or are you saying that there
are already enemies inside?
左の数字は アイテムのカードナンバーで 右のほうは　記号が アイテムの入手難度のことね。
That would be admitting that your En
is completely worthless, would it not?
難易度ランクは　ＳＳからＨまで １０段階あって
You're absolutely correct.
Ｆは　下から３番目ね。
If my En is focused only outside, it cannot detect
記号の横の数字は　アイテムの カード化限度枚数のことね。
any attack from underground.
ん　つまり このアイテムカードは…。 まぁ　くずアイテムかな。
In addition, my En is not capable of recognizing
an enemy that is already inside.
うわ！ キャ！
Do you mean Komugi?
わぁ！ うわ！ あっ！ あっ！ 初めて見る顔だ… むごいのぉ 一緒にゲームに参加した奴だ
No, eleven soldiers still remain within the palace, and they are free to enter and leave at will.
ねぇ　何があったの？ 突然　体が爆発したんだ 内側から　ボンとよ。 ゲームに参加して　まだ数時間 もう犠牲者が…
A check is performed each time someone enters, but if the soldier were being
controlled by the enemy, it would be difficult to know for sure. That means—
この圧倒的な死体の存在感 とてもゲームとは思えない
Enough. You may use En on the first floor of the palace!
実際に 命の危険を伴うゲーム…
That will permit you to guard
against any underground attack! Tell everyone that no one is allowed
on the second floor or above.
消えた！ 現実世界に戻ったんだろ ゲームオーバーさ。
Should an intruder come, I shall
deal with them personally.
ねぇ　キルア
Likewise, you will not come unless summoned!
まさか　さっき　キルアが かけられた魔法って…。
If you disturb me, it will
have violent consequences!
分からない…。 安心しな。
The other Ants
このゲームに そんなスペルは存在しない。
were never allowed on or above the second floor...
スペル？ 君が言う　魔法のようなものだ。
But where do I go now? The central stairway connecting the
first and second floors, I suppose...
あいつが死んだのは 他のプレーヤーによる 「念」のせいだ。 「念」？
If an intruder comes from underground, you will be in position to deal with them.
それって　プレーヤー同士で 殺し合いをしてるってこと？
Still, the King's been in a bad mood lately.
一体　何で？ プレーヤー狩りさ。 プレーヤー狩り？ 詳しいことは　後で教えてやる。
Is he upset about losing
all those Gungi matches?
それより　俺達と組まないか？
I have an idea as to the cause of his irritation.
確実に　ゲームを クリアできる方法がある。 えっ？ 興味があるなら　ついて来てくれ。
My ability, Spiritual Message, would be
able to confirm my suspicions.
この先に　俺の仲間もいる。 どうする？ うん　うさんくさいな。
However, that would be an insult to the King!
スタート直後に もう嫌な目に遭ってるし。
No, I'm just making excuses...
君は　確か
The truth is that I'm afraid.
ここに来る途中　他のプレーヤーに スペルの攻撃を受けてたね。
So afraid of what it is
もしかして　ずっと見てたの？ 俺達のこと。 ああ　俺だけじゃ　ない。 さまざまな連中が あのスタート地点を見張っている。
that grows inside the King even as we speak, I cannot bear it...
君を攻撃したスペルについてもね。 やけに気前がいいね。
Tsk, the rain washed away the scent.
何か　裏があるとしか思えないぜ。
But now I have the answer.
やむを得ないのさ。 このゲームの難しさ いやらしさ　恐ろしさ それが分かって初めて
The intruder hid here to
check the second floor, but instead of going upstairs, he exited.
俺達の誘いに 耳を貸すようになるからな。
Something made him give up his mission? Or did he accomplish his objective?
まぁ　とにかく　初めて 来たばかりの君達にとって
No, he may have used his power!
情報を聞くだけでも 有意義だと思うがね。
I should probably warn you...
何で　初めてだって思うの？ 途中でゲームから抜けて
If any of you go to the second
floor, the King will kill you.
また　戻って来たのかも しれないだろ。
Tell everyone else in the palace.
ブック。
Wings!
これが　君達が 初心者だという証拠だ。
What if the intruder has the power to fly? The shoes and scent could have
been there to mislead us.
慣れた者なら　相手が バインダーを出したら　すぐ 自分もバインダーを出す。
He could have flown up to the second floor! Youpi-dono...
スペルカードでしか 防げないからな。
Huh? Uh, er...
ってことは　キルアが かけられたスペルも…。
Pitou is monitoring the palace with En.
カードでしか防げない。 たとえ　カードを 持ってなかったとしても
If they'd gone to the second floor,
they would have been caught...
バインダーを出す！ ハッタリは大事だ。
Ah, sorry... It's not important. Huh?
ブック。 ねぇ　スペルのカードは どうやって手に入れるの？
That doesn't make sense! Then how did the intruder reach the stairway?! Youpi-dono...
最も簡単なのは 魔法都市　マサドラへ行くことだ。 マサドラ？
Huh? What is it? Has Pitou-dono ever ceased to use En?
((「リターン」オン！ マサドラへ！))
For example, that day last week when it rained?
キルア　行ってみようよ。
What? You didn't hear what happened?
キルアにかけられた スペルも気になるし。
There was a huge uproar...
ねっ！
The King tore off his own arm!
ああ。
Pitou had to heal the King,
so Pouf was using his En instead.
これで全部か？
Wouldn't it be just as large as Pitou's?
じゃあ　始めようか。
No, I'd guess that Pouf's En only
reached as far as the stairway. The intruder saw that aura, and gave up on ascending!
たった今　また一人 プレーヤーがやられた。 君達と時を同じくして来た人物だ。 腹が　ふっ飛んでたよ。
That all makes sense. The question is what the
intruder's objective was, and whether he's still hiding around here.
ボマーの仕業だ。 ボマー？
Do I tell Youpi?
彼の死は スペルによるものではない。
No, I can't do that...
このゲームのスペルの中には
I should report this to Pitou or Pouf.
人を殺傷する類いのものは 一つもない。
Pouf would be the best choice. And if possible, I need to determine
故に　君達が かけられたスペルで負傷したり
what the intruder's objective was.
ましてや 死ぬことなど　あり得ない。
Otherwise, my report would be
スペルは　全部で４０種類。 その中で 君達が受けたスペルは　調査型
that the intruder somehow
made it inside the palace, but turned and ran when he felt Pouf's En. I won't get any credit.
「トレース」か 「アドヒージョン」のいずれか。 ひと言で言うと そのスペルをかけられた
I can make up an objective, but if the intruder is captured,
they'll find out I lied.
プレーヤーの情報が 全て　敵に筒抜けになる。 そうか　それで　あの時… それらのスペルを 新参プレーヤーにかけるため
But if I tell the Royal Guard my suspicions
and the intruder is never found, it would only waste their time
and damage my own standing.
スタート地点で 見張ってる連中がいる。
Is that Bizeff's cell phone again?! I have a great idea...
そして　貴重なカードを手に入れたら すぐに現れ　強奪する。
So the intruder captured one of my men.
最悪の場合は 命を落とすこともある。
According to Leol, that intruder
has the ability to teleport.
さっきの奴みたいにか？ 俺は　そう簡単に　やられねえ。
I believe that he and the
woman are working together. They probably teleported out together.
プレーヤー狩りを目的とした 最も過激な奴ら　その中の１人
Damn, but why would they do that? Yes, that's the question.
「ボマー」と呼ばれる奴の仕業だ。
However, I've discerned their objective. What is it?
ボマー…。 このゲームで アイテムカードをゲットする方法は
To blow up the palace. That's a lie.
大きく分けて３つ それが分かるか？
What? We must tell the Royal Guard! Wait.
うん…　自分で探す！
Don't be in such a rush. We can tell them after we've found the bomb.
他のプレーヤーから奪う。 うん　大きく分ければ　その３つだ。
There's no time! Calm down, and consider this
from their perspective... Eh?
しかし最近　他のプレーヤーから 強引に奪う者が増えて来た。
If they want to blow up the palace,
they'll wait until they're sure the King is here. When would that be?
原因は　カードの入手難度と カード化限度枚数のシステムだ。
When all the citizens have assembled... Right before the ceremony begins!
自力でカードを 入手できない者達が
There will be five million humans! What a sight that will be to see...
力ずくで他の者のカードを奪う。
Just imagine looking down on them!
そして　抵抗する者は簡単に殺す。
The King would not allow a double
to steal that gratification from him!
殺せば指輪は消滅し カードデータも消えるが
So he will be there in person!
その分　カード化できる アイテムが増えるからだ。
It's only logical to assume the enemy
reached the same conclusion. True...
相手を殺してしまったら カードは奪えない。
I've stood at the former Supreme Leader's
side for many of these celebrations...
当初　このルールは　プレーヤー同士の 殺し合い防止が目的だったはず。
The experience brings indescribable
pleasure beyond even sexual gratification.
しかし　今は それが裏目に出ている。
We still have over half a day
before the ceremony.
このゲームが世に出て １０年以上。 この煮詰まった状況を 打破しない限り
If I use my nose to track the intruder, we can find the bomb with time to spare.
殺りくは　繰り返される。 だから俺達が　ピリオドを打つ！
If we have proof when we report to the
Royal Guard, we'll look much better.
同志を募り　ゲームを攻略する。 協力してほしい！
If we save the King's life, they'll be quite grateful.
カードを得る方法は？ １　自力探索　２　トレード
Right? Yes... That's true.
３　奪取…　どれになるんだ？
As soon as I find the bomb, I'll contact you.
３だ。
Okay, that sounds good.
厳密に言えば ３つとも全部使うが 特に３が重要ってことだろ？ 何だよ　じゃあ　結局 力ずくで奪うのか？
The coward finally calmed down?
違う！　少なくとも 俺達は暴力を使わない！ スペル。
I'm getting closer to becoming
the King behind the scenes!
スペルの中のカードを 奪うスペル。
Seven minutes to go.
それを防御するスペルがあるんだ。
I'll give a call when it's down to one minute.
そのスペルカードを 俺達が独占する。
Assemble near the exit then.
プレーヤーを悩ませ続けた カード化限度枚数
Until then, stand by.
それを逆手にとる。
Meleoron, about your power...
他にクリアする方法は　ない。
I know.
過去　いろいろなプレーヤーに 会ったが　結論は同じ。
I'll tap your shoulder ten seconds
before I need to breathe...
カードを求めても 結局　奪われてしまう。
And then, I'll tap you again when
I start to hold my breath again!
それは　このゲームの前提が カードの奪い合いだからだ。
You don't need to push your limits.
奪われるリスクを 限りなくゼロにし
You should catch your breath
whenever you need to.
確実にカードを奪う。 あんた達　肝心なこと 言ってないだろ。
When God's Accomplice isn't active,
you can trust me to handle things.
君達　バッテラ氏の依頼で ここに参加したんだろ？
Why don't you have a smoke?
承知の上での勧誘か。 ああ。
If you underestimate their sense
of smell, you'll die quickly...
俺達も　バッテラ氏に雇われて プレーしている。 故に　クリア報酬は５００億。
Tracking someone by the smell of
cigarette smoke is simple for them.
それを仲間全員で山分けする。
We could be knocked out the
second I take my first breath...
現在　仲間は５３名。
The boss will be putting up a smokescreen
when we go in. It'll be fine.
残り必要なスペルカード集めに２か月 勝負に出て１か月 ３か月でクリアだ。
I know, but I'd rather avoid unnecessary risk.
もちろん　仲間に入ってくれたら
I don't want to regret my decision.
君達に　今　かかっている スペルも解除する。
The Royal Guard is on the move.
入るぜ。 ５００億を山分けってのは 正直キツいが
The three of them gathered above the
front gate to discuss something.
３か月でクリアっていう 期限つきが気に入った。
Pitou stayed there, and Youpi went back inside.
あんたは　どうだい？ 一つ　聞くが
Pouf returned to the air to scatter his scales, so I don't think anything has changed.
例えば　俺が入手難度ＳＳのカードを 単独でゲットしたら　報酬は？
I'll let you know if anything else happens.
もちろん　そのランクなら ５億で取引している。
Yeah, until we leave, feed us as
much information as you can.
ＯＫ　入ろう。 君達は　どうする？
Essentially, that eliminates the
possibility of the Royal Guard being out of the palace.
キルア　ごめん。
Essentially, but not completely...
ん？　何が？ 俺は　いい 自力でプレーするから。
Well, I guarantee that they'll be near the King. You can't guarantee anything.
あ…。
We have to be prepared for any possibility, or we'll be slow to react when
something goes wrong!
リーダーが　そう言うんでね 俺もパス。
You only say that because you don't
understand how loyal they are.
おい　ゴン！　待てってば！
It's impossible that they'd leave the King!
君は　どうする？
The Royal Guard is always with the King!
では　まず スペル解除のため
And it's fine to believe that! But we should prepare for any exceptions!
君達には　一度 ゲームの外に出てもらう。
Give me an example of one
of these exceptions!
ゲームに戻って来たら　そのまま スタート地点で待機しててくれ。
Honestly, how can they be having
a dispute at the last second?
こちらから　迎えに行く。
One exception could be a woman...
もし　フリーポケットに カードがあれば 今のうちに渡してもらおう。 なぜ？
Isn't one of the King's objectives to reproduce?
ゲームの外に出たら フリーポケットのカードデータは
I wasn't sure what the King was doing in
the palace, but he was reproducing. That must be it.
全て消えてしまうんだ。
I see...
確か　指定ポケットのほうは 出し入れする際 オートセーブされるんだよなぁ。
That would give the King a reason to keep
the Royal Guard from his bedroom...
ああ　だが１０日以内に 戻って来ないと データは消滅する。 君達が　その期限内に 戻って来なければ
Perhaps Bizeff was bringing
women in for the King.
リタイアしたものとみなす いいね？
Palm and the King?!
大丈夫　仲間が迎えに来た。
We're sticking to the plan...
使うのは　「リーブ」のカードだ。
Gon has no idea what they're talking about. I'm glad we realized this before we set out.
おい　ゴンってばよ。 どういうことだか説明しろよ。
If we'd seen something like
that without warning, we'd have frozen in our tracks.
ふぅ…。
Get it now? You can never overthink something.
ごめんね　キルア！　どうしても 我慢できなくなっちゃって。
There are probably other unexpected
situations that we haven't considered yet.
いや　だから　「ごめん」の意味 分かんねえって。 だって　これで キルアのスペルは
Yes, something is still bothering me. Gon...
当分　かかりっ放しに なっちゃったし。
Do you understand?
何だ　んなことか 別に問題ねえよ。
Let Palm take care of herself!
でも　俺の親父捜しのために
No matter what you see,
you must stay focused on Pitou.
キルアにもゲームに 参加してもらってるのに…。 違うよ　俺がゲームに 参加してるのは…
Yeah! It bothers me, but whether
a woman's involved or not, I believe we should be prepared
for a third party in the palace.
それよか　さっき 何で怒ってたんだよ？
I have a feeling that the third party is causing my anxiety.
だって　あいつら ジンの作ったゲームを 殺りくだとか 奪い合いが前提だとか
Why did the King injure himself?
悪いふうにばっか言うんだもん。
Hold on... That was just a theory of yours.
俺は　ジンの言う通り このゲームを楽しもうと思った。
Yeah, but you agreed that there
was no other logical explanation.
スタート地点に立った時 確かに　ひと筋縄では行かないと 思ったけど
You're contradicting yourself...
それは ゲームに参加している　みんなが
Didn't you say there could be other exceptions?
真剣にゲームを 楽しんでると思ったから。 実際に人が死んでるけど 怖いのは　ゲームじゃなくて
Following that logic, Pitou could have stopped using En
for other, unexpected reasons.
プレーヤーの考え方だよ。
I understand that...
他の人を傷つけてまで カードを取ろうとするなんて。 そうか？　俺は　ありだと思うぜ。
But something doesn't feel right. With three minutes left to go, is this
something worth thinking about?
キルア　本気で言ってんの？
Yeah.
だからこその ハンター専用ゲームだろ。
Yeah, think about it...
でも…。 殺しは　なしさ 俺だって　そこは賛成だよ。
When would you try to hurt yourself?
勝ったほうが相手のカードを もらえるってのは　どうだ？ あっ　ありだ。 なっ？
When I couldn't forgive myself...
俺に　スペルをかけた奴だって あの連中の作戦だって
When you couldn't forgive yourself?
ゲームとして　まっとうな やり方だと思うぜ。
That's the logical conclusion...
うん。 やり方は　ハメみたいで カッコ悪いけどな。 まっ　とにかく あんな奴らは　ほっといて
But that would mean the King
is a ruler with personal pride, and not just a cold tyrant.
俺達は　ゲームを楽しもうぜ。 キルア。 ん？ ありがと！
True. For the sake of his pride, he's willing to endure pain.
キルアと一緒に ここに来られて…　ううん
Speaking from experience, people like him will never
be willing to compromise.
キルアと会えて 俺　本当に　よかったよ！
If the leader refuses to compromise,
neither will the Royal Guard.
やめろよ　バカ　恥ずいだろ。 何で？　俺　ホントに そう思ってるんだよ。
You should assume that combat
will be our only option!
逆だよ…　ゴン　俺なんだ
Morel was able to sum everything up... But he's wrong. The King's self-injury...
俺のほうこそ　お前に会えて 本当に　よかった
The third party... We still haven't correctly
deduced what happened.
なるほど　そういう訳…
I have a feeling...
それにしても　いいわねぇ 若い男の子の無垢な友情
that the truth has the potential
to completely ruin our plans! It's time!
なんか　むちゃくちゃに してやりたい気分
One minute to go. Gather around.